<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about-me/</guid>
      <description>About MeAcademic HistoryOriginally I attended the Liberal Arts &amp;amp; Science Academy (LASA) in north-east Austin for high school, were I became intrigued and inspired by the world of biology. Being active participant in the Robotics Club, I always thought I would go on to major in some field of engineering, though my eye was on Biomedical engineering. After taking a gap year where I volunteered abroad working in gardening, agriculture, and horticulture work I decided to start my major off in a more broad field so as to allow myself time and space to be exposed to wider variety of future possibilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python List &amp; Dictionary Comprehension</title>
      <link>/2020/05/14/python-list-dictionary-comprehension/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/14/python-list-dictionary-comprehension/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been hearing how wonderful python is from some of my computer science friends for a very long time now, so I’ve been looking forward to this portion of the class for quite a while. After spending a bit of time perusing the interwebs about different useful, and fun, applications of python, I stumbled upon a very well artiuclated video about the use of dictionaries and lists in python, and how they work very well together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>ModelingFind data/Introduction/Tidying: I chose to work again with my dataset from project one because it revealed some interesting correlations. The original dataset has 3,191 observations and 534 Variables stemming from many different national data servers. I selected for 6 particular variables. Each observation contains the population of a particular city (not selected for/identified here but sourced from the Census Population Estimates) within a state in the US, and the percentage of that population that experienced insufficient sleep (data sourced from the Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/project1_sofa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1_sofa/</guid>
      <description>Data Wrangling and Data ExplorationFind data/Introduction:The original dataset I chose has 3,191 observations and 534 Variables stemming from many different national data servers. I selected for 6 particular variables. Each observation is labeled by a unique digit code, which I used later as the primary key to join the two self-made portions of the dataset back into one. The digit code was created for the dataset to label each unique observation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>