<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python List &amp; Dictionary Comprehension</title>
      <link>/2020/05/14/python-list-dictionary-comprehension/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/14/python-list-dictionary-comprehension/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been hearing how wonderful python is from some of my computer science friends for a very long time now, so I’ve been looking forward to this portion of the class for quite a while. After spending a bit of time perusing the interwebs about different useful, and fun, applications of python, I stumbled upon a very well artiuclated video about the use of dictionaries and lists in python, and how they work very well together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/project1_sofa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1_sofa/</guid>
      <description>Data Wrangling and Data ExplorationInstructionsA knitted R Markdown document (as a PDF) and the raw R Markdown file (as .Rmd) should both be submitted to Canvas by 11:59pm on 3/8/2020. These two documents will be graded jointly, so they must be consistent (i.e., don’t change the R Markdown file without also updating the knitted document).
Find data/Introduction:The original dataset I chose has 3,191 observations and 534 Variables stemming from many different national data servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>ModelingFind data/Introduction/Tidying: I chose to work again with my dataset from project one because it revealed some interesting correlations. The original dataset has 3,191 observations and 534 Variables stemming from many different national data servers. I selected for 6 particular variables. Each observation contains the population of a particular city (not selected for/identified here but sourced from the Census Population Estimates) within a state in the US, and the percentage of that population that experienced insufficient sleep (data sourced from the Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>